A Guide to the Dining Services at JMU Oral Histories, 2004: SdArch 36
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Dining Services at JMU Oral Histories
2004
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Torisky, Danielle
SdArch 36
4
.5 cubic feet; 8 folders, 8 audiocassettes, 1 cd
Dining Services at JMU Oral Histories, 2004, is comprised audio recordings, transcripts, and research notes related to seven interviews conducted by Danielle Torisky with individuals regarding their experiences with dining services at James Madison University.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research within the Special Collections Reading Room. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the James Madison University Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Acquisition Information
Materials were donated by Danielle Torisky on October 9, 2007.
Arrangement
Interviews are arranged alphabetically by last name.
Bio/Historical Note
Dr. Danielle Torisky is an Associate Professor in the Dietetics Program at James Madison University. In 2003 she was the recipient of a Burruss Grant, awarded by James Madison University Libraries to research the history of JMU's Dining Services from 1908-2004. Torisky conducted a series of interviews which contributed to the research paper, "History of Dining Services at JMU," published by Torisky in 2007. It was intended to support exhibits and other events in the celebration of the JMU Centennial in 2008.
Related Materials
Torisky, Danielle M. "History of Dining Services at James Madison University," 2007.
Scope and Content
Dining Services at JMU Oral Histories, 2004, is comprised audio recordings, transcripts, and research notes related to seven interviews Torisky conducted with individuals regarding their experiences with dining services at James Madison University. Narrators include the Campus Dietition, several JMU alumnae, the Director of Vending Services, the former Controller of Dining Services, and a faculty member of the Health Science Department. They recall various dining services facilities, including "D-Hall" and PC Dukes, experiences with vendors such as Aramark and Marriott, and memories of eating experiences on campus. The materials also include a digital copy of the research paper, "History of Dining Services at James Madison University," authored by Torisky in 2007.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Burruss, Julian Ashby, 1876-1947; State Normal and Industrial School for Women (Harrisonburg, Va.) -- History; State Teachers College at Harrisonburg (Harrisonburg, Va.) -- History; Madison College -- History; James Madison University -- History; James Madison University -- Buildings; James Madison University -- Buildings -- History; College students -- Nutrition -- Virginia; Education, Higher -- Virginia -- History
Genre and Form Terms:
oral histories (literary works)
- History of Dining Services at James Madison University, Danielle M. Torsky, PhD, RD, Health Sciences Department, Dietetics Program, July 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA036-OP-001)
- JMU Dining Services Surveys, 2004
- SdArch 36-1: Michele Cavoto, interviewed by Danielle Torisky, November 15, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Transcript and supporting documents (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Original audiocassette (Box 1, Audiocassette SA036-CS-001)
  - Preservation master (Box 1, Audiocassette SA036-CS-008)
- SdArch 36-2: Jane Doe, interviewed by Danielle Torisky, August 23, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Conditions Governing Access
  The name of the narrator was changed by Torisky, at the request of the narrator.
- SdArch 36-3: Leigh Ann and Melissa Hallowell, interviewed by Danielle Torisky, October 22, 2004
  - Transcript and supporting documents (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Original audiocassette (Box 1, Audiocassette SA036-CS-001)
  - Preservation master (Box 1, Audiocassette SA036-CS-008)
- SdArch 36-4: Dolly Lawson, interviewed by Danielle Torisky, September 15, 2004
  - Transcript and supporting documents (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Original audiocassette (Box 1, Audiocassette SA036-CS-002)
  - Preservation master (Box 1, Audiocassette SA036-CS-006)
- SdArch 36-5: Linda Leffel, interviewed by Danielle Torisky, June 8, 2004
  - Transcript and supporting documents (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Original audiocassette (Box 1, Audiocassette SA036-CS-002)
  - Preservation master (Box 1, Audiocassette SA036-CS-006)
- SdArch 36-6: Horace T. Moody, interviewed by Danielle Torisky, November 19, 2004
  - Transcript and supporting documents (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Original audiocassette (Box 1, Audiocassette SA036-CS-003)
  - Preservation master (Box 1, Audiocassette SA036-CS-007)
- SdArch 36-7: Maria T. (Terry) Wessel, interviewed by Danielle Torisky, August 23, 2005
  - Transcript and supporting documents (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Original audiocassette (Box 1, Audiocassette SA036-CS-004)
  - Preservation master (Box 1, Audiocassette SA036-CS-005)